

João Devson Mucavel

Nationality: Mozambican Date of birth: 09/06/1991 Gender: Male

Phone number: (+258) 844559091 **Phone number:** (+258) 822759287

Email address: <u>joaodevsonm@gmail.com</u> **Skype:** joaodevsonm

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joão-devson-mucavel-116072aa/

Q GitHub: https://github.com/devassse

ambigue)

Website: https://portfolio-devassses-projects.vercel.app

• Home: Av. Acordos de Lusaka Matola Gare - Nwamartibyana Q7, 1100 Maputo (Moz

ABOUT ME

Born on June 9, 1991, I completed the basic education in 2006 and general secondary education in 2008. Graduated in Computer Systems Programming from the Instituto Industrial e de Computação Armando Emílio Guebuza in 2014 and attended the Systems Administration course of Computing Information and Networks at the University of São Tomás de Moçambique (1st year only).

With around 8 years of professional experience. Throughout this period I came across situations that prepared me to increasingly face the difficulties that may arise in the labor sector.

My biggest project was developing an AI solution, capable of identifying and helping to mitigate possible accidents at work. I used emerging technologies on the market, with emphasis on Python.

I intend to study a degree in Computer Systems Programming and Telecommunications at the Escola Superior de Ciências Náuticas de Moçambique. My academic background, combined with the practical skills acquired, motivates me to continually seek new opportunities for learning and growth in the technology area.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software developer

ITGest Mozambique [04/2019 - Current]

City: Maputo | Country: Mozambique

Software developer:

- Working on the implementation of BM Eventos at Banco de Moçambique.
- I worked on an AI project *IDSmartWorld*: Detector of objects and dangerous situations, supporting the HST sector and generating reports for analysis and warning about possible dangers.
- I worked on the design and development of a solution for Event Management IDEvents.
- I worked in Analysis to develop a Card and POS Clearing, Reconciliation and Settlement Solution for a client Banking Institutions.
- I worked on implementing a Service Desk solution at Banco de Moçambique: *ID4Service*.
- I worked on the development of a User Support Management platform/solution (Service Desk ID4Service).
- I worked on the project to design and develop the Account Opening and Payment Methods Contracting Workflow (Cards and Checks) for MOZA BANCO.
- I worked on a solution for Management and Organization of Common Rooms (spaces) ID4Meetings.
- I worked on a Queue Management platform (we call it *Ghahula*) to organize meal times at Copa, which is currently in use. Being accessible from the QR Code.

Web developer

Brand Lovers [08/2018 – 03/2019]

City: Maputo | Country: Mozambique

Web Developer:

• Development of Web platforms and Websites (HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Php, Wordpress).

Software developer

Self-employed [07/2017 - Current]

City: Maputo | Country: Mozambique

With the expression - self-employed - I refer to a phase in which I was without work for someone else.

During this period, I got involved in personal projects, with the aim of selling:

- eb Applications Based on Java EE:
 - One of these applications gave us the possibility of winning a contest **Super Mentores**
- I worked on developing Desktop and Mobile applications (Android and iOS).
- I worked on (IoT, VR & AR) projects.

Web developer

FNB Moçambique [06/2017 – 07/2017]

City: Maputo | Country: Mozambique

• Development of the current website and some improvements to the existing Internet Banking application. (30-day project in collaboration with Cloud Digital Arts).

Software developer

Cloud Digital Arts [04/2014 - 07/2017]

City: Maputo | Country: Mozambique

- Website Development (HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Wordpress).
- Development of Technological and Interactive Solutions.

Software developer

SanTech, Lda [02/2014 – 06/2014]

City: Maputo | Country: Mozambique

Trainee (Intern):

• Development of SEGE - Electronic School Management System - (ZK, JavaEE).

Computer Infrastructures and Networks / Help Desk

LAM - Linhas Aérias de Moçambique [08/2013 - 11/2013]

City: Maputo | Country: Mozambique

Trainee (Intern):

- Maintenance of Network and Cabling Systems.
- · Helpdesk.

Air conditioning and refrigeration technician

[2011 - 2011]

City: Maputo | Country: Mozambique

Repair and Maintenance of Refrigeration Devices - Air Conditioning Devices:

· Glaciers, Freezers, Cold Rooms.

Inquisitor

[2010 - 2010]

City: Maputo | Country: Mozambique

Intercampus - Estudos de mercados.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Programação de Sistemas Informáticos

Armando Emílio Guebuza Industrial and Computing Institute [02/2011 - 07/2013]

City: Maputo | Country: Mozambique

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Português | Xangana | Ronga

Other language(s):

Japanese

LISTENING A1 READING A1 WRITING A1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION A1 SPOKEN INTERACTION A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Virtual Reality / Augmented reality: Vuforia / IoT/Mobile Device Management

SOCIAL AND POLITICAL ACTIVITIES

Social and communication skills

- Good communication skills with the work team acquired over the years in the job market.
- Improved public speaking skills gained from giving public religious speeches.

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: C1

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Organization skills

- Good ability to interact with employees to exchange experiences and questions that may arise.
- Ability to work without supervision as long as tasks are clearly defined.